Guide to the Donald Windham and Sandy Campbell Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- May 2011 Acquisition, 1805-2010; 40.14; (58 boxes) + 2 broadsides
  - Photographs, circa 1895-1999; Series IV; 7.08; (8 boxes)
    - Living Room photographs, 1895-1985
      - Capote, Truman, Harper Lee and unknown man with child (Box 38)
        Includes three photographs which were originally framed with each other.
      - Campbell, Monty (?) - as child, 1895 (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Monty (?) - as child, colored photograph, 1895 (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Monty - framed (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Monty and Jiny, 1930 (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Monty and Jiny, with Sandy, circa 1922 (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Sandy, circa 1943 (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Sandy, 1943 (Box 38)
        Contains three Paul Cadmus photographs of Sandy Campbell.
      - Campbell, Sandy - front door, Westfield, circa 1943 (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Sandy - Gotham Book Mart (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Sandy - passport photo, 1948 (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Sandy and unidentified woman, 1954 (Box 38)
      - Campbell, Sandy - as child, 1933 (Box 38)
      - Clift, Montgomery, 1940s (Box 38)
        Contains a photograph by Alfredo Valente.
      - Clipping - statue (Box 38)
      - Crane, Hart, 1930; 2 (Box 38)
        Includes photographs of Hart Crane by Walker Evans.
      - Donald Windham's mother and other girl (Box 38)
      - Empty metal picture locket with initials M.E.P. (Box 38)
      - Faulkner, William (Box 38)
      - Joffrion, Doris - age 17, New Orleans, framed, 1910s (Box 38)
        Contains a picture of Sandy Campbell's mother.
      - Kirstein, Fidelma - Fairfield, 1985 July (Box 38)
      - LeClercq, Tanaquil (Box 38)
      - LeClercq, Tanaquil, cased photograph (Box 38)
      - LeClercq, Tanaquil (?) - locket (Box 38)
      - LeClercq, Tanaquil and George Balanchine, cased photograph (Box 38)
      - Mann, Thomas, 1942 (Box 38)
      - McCullers, Carson (Box 38)
        Image by Carl Van Vechten.
      - Moore, Marianne - quote card (Box 38)
      - O'Neill, Eugene, 1935 (Box 38)
      - Phillips, Margaret and Tony Smith, 1948 (Box 38)
        Contains a photograph of Margaret Phillips and Tony Smith at a party for Summer and Smoke.
      - Smith, Tony (?), circa 1950 (Box 38)
      - Strindberg, August, 1895 (Box 38)
      - Williams, Tennessee, 1948 (Box 38)
      - Unidentified colored portrait of child, framed. (Box 38)
        This portrait may be of Donald Windham, circa 1920s.
      - Unidentified men, undated, 1961 (Box 38)
        Contains two photographs of unidentified men.
      - Unidentified woman and child (Box 38)
      - White House invitation with Harry Truman's signature, 1945 (Box 38)
      - Windham, Donald, Sandy Campbell, Tanaquil LeClercq and George Balanchine, 1959 (Box 38)
      - Windham, Donald, Tanaquil LeClercq and George Balanchine, 1959 (Box 38)
  - Artwork, 1805, 1827, circa 1920-1979; Series V; 3.88; (17 boxes)
    - George Platt Lynes photographs - "One", 2 (Box 39)
    - George Platt Lynes photographs - "Two" (Box 39)
    - George Platt Lynes photographs - "Melton, Windham, Campbell" (Box 39)
    - PaJaMa photographs - includes Paul Cadmus, Jared & Margaret French material, 3 (Box 39)
    - "Collaged Books - Clippings Erotic - Male", 3 (Box 39)
    - Erotic collage clippings, 4 (Box 39)
    - Erotic photographs, 6 (Box 39)
    - Clippings and collages, 3 (Box 40)
    - Stamp collection (Box 40)
    - Collage materials - loose clippings (Box 40)
    - Collage materials - cards and other misc. materials, clippings (Box 40)
    - Collage materials - pages from books, "Mr. Salinger" forum (Box 40)
    - Donald Windham's cutouts (Box 40)
    - Sketches (Box 40)
    - View publication, 1942 (Box 41 Oversize)
    - Photographs, circa 1980s (Box 41 Oversize)
      Includes a photograph of Donald Windham, circa1980, and a William Wolf photograph.
    - Erotic collages (Box 41 Oversize)
    - Collage materials, 3 (Box 41 Oversize)
    - Collage materials, 3 (Box 40)
    - George Platt Lynes photograph (Box 40)
    - Collage within A Dillehia De La Belle's Art (Box 40)
    - Collage of boy - framed (Box 42 Oversize)
    - United States Penitentiary postcard collage - framed (Box 43 Oversize)
    - "What Do You See When You Look Out Your Window at Night?" collage - Joseph Cornell - framed (Box 44 Oversize)
    - "The Artist as Subject: Paul Cadmus" - printed invitation, 1993 (Box 45 Oversize)
    - Leonardo da Vinci flower study reprint - "Windham 2927 B" - framed (Box 45 Oversize)
    - "Tennessee Williams Legacy: An Eloquence and Amplitude of Feeling" - newspaper article by Arthur Miller - framed, 1984 (Box 46 Oversize)
    - Flower collage - Donald Windham - framed (Box 47 Oversize)
    - Envelope and easter card - Alice B. Toklas - framed (Box 48 Oversize)
    - Postcard collage - Joseph Cornell - framed (Box 49 Oversize)
    - Envelope and card - E.M. Forster - framed (Box 50 Oversize)
    - Drawings of Don Windham - Paul Cadmus, circa 1941; 2 (Box 51)
      Originally framed.
    - Drawings of Sandy Campbell - Paul Cadmus, circa 1943; 4 (Box 51)
    - Drawing of Sandy Campbell in Three Poses - Paul Cadmus, circa 1943 (Box 51)
    - "Syngnathus and Tetrodon - J. Pass - engraved for the Encyclopedia of Lendinesnsis", 1805, 1827, undated (Box 52 Oversize)
      Also includes "Fialaria and Fistularia - J. Pass - Published as the Act Directs, May 18th 1805" and pen drawing of animals.
    - Cover design for Stone in the Hourglass (Box 52 Oversize)
      Designed by Donald Windham using Fritz Bultman collage
    - "Original Cover Design for Two People" - Coward-McCann, Inc. (Box 52 Oversize)
    - "Signed Trimmed Tanaquil Covers" (three) - Tony Smith (Box 52 Oversize)
    - The Balloon Tree - Donald Windham - complete original cut-out illustrations, manuscript, etc. (Box 52 Oversize)
    - "Miousis - P[C?] 29", circa 1929 (Box 52 Oversize)
      Also includes a copy of "Jupiter Amoreaux D'Anthiope - Se transforme en statute".
    - "Don Windham - Cadmus 1941", framed drawing, 2 (Box 53 Oversize)
    - Sandy Campbell - Paul Cadmus, framed drawing, 1943 (Box 53 Oversize)
    - "PaJaMa" - Paul Cadmus and Donald Windham, Fire Island - photograph by Jared French, framed, circa 1941 (Box 53 Oversize)
    - You Touched Me! promotional poster - Don Freeman, framed (Box 54 Oversize)
    - "Cover Designs (front-back) for Tennessee Williams Letters to Donald Windham 1940-1976, framed (Box 55 Oversize)
    - "PaJaMa (Jared French)" - Donald Windham and Fred Milton, framed photograph (Box 53 Oversize)
    - "A Happy New Year" - Tennessee Williams, framed drawing (Box 53 Oversize)
  - Office files, circa 1940-2010; Series VI; 4; (4 boxes)
    - Misc. notebook, notebook sheets (Box 56)
    - A - artists' postcards (Box 56)
    - B - George Brown (Box 56)
    - D - Tim Dlugos (Box 56)
    - D - Donald Downes, 1961-1980; 2 (Box 56)
    - F- E.M. Forster (Box 56)
    - G - Giovanni's Room (Box 56)
    - H - Richard Harwell, Univ. of GA, 1976-1986; 2 (Box 56)
    - H - Winston R. Holt - royalty statements (Box 56)
    - H - Winston Rinehart Holt (Box 56)
    - L - Erich Linder - Mattiole (Box 56)
    - L - Joseph LeSueur (Box 56)
    - M - Melton - Tennessee exchange regarding Rader (Box 56)
    - M - William Morrow (Box 56)
    - M - William Morrow & Co. - Lost Friendships business (Box 56)
    - M - William Morrow & Co. - Lost Friendships misc. (Box 56)
    - M - William Morrow & Co. - Lost Friendships responses (Box 56)
    - N - "New Songs Will Be Misunderstood" (Box 56)
    - P - Popular Library (Box 56)
    - P - Paragon House (Box 56)
    - P - George Parsons, 2 (Box 56)
    - S - Frances Steloff (Box 56)
    - S - Allen W. Schwartz (Greenbaum, Wolff, Ernst) (Box 56)
    - T - Tanaquil - business, 1972-1976 (Box 56)
    - T - Tanaquil - reviews, publicity (Box 56)
    - T - Kenneth Tynan (Box 56)
    - W - Tennessee Williams' Letters to Donald Windham - introduction, notes (Box 56)
    - W - Posthumous T.W. correspondence (Spoto-Leurich etc.) (Box 56)
    - W - Tennessee Williams' Letters to Donald Windham - reviews, publicity (Box 56)
    - W - "P.S.: Being 'Friends Again' with Tennessee" (Box 56)
    - Biographical material (Box 57)
    - Loose-leaf notebooks, clippings, etc., 1941-1943; 2 (Box 57)
    - Loose materials from journals, 1949-1963; 2 (Box 57)
    - B - Billy Budd (Box 57)
    - E - Drafts of parts of Emblems of Conduct (some proposed chapters not included) (Box 57)
    - E - Eyes of Finnigan (Box 57)
    - F - Fichi D' India (Box 57)
    - F - Charles Henri Ford (Box 57)
    - G - Craig Gray - thesis on D.W.'s writings (Box 57)
    - H - The Hero Continues (play) (Box 57)
    - I - In Fair Verona (Box 57)
    - K - The Kelly Boys (Box 57)
    - L - Like a Flower (Box 57)
    - M - Mother's letters about homeplace (Box 57)
    - N - Notes on D.H. Lawrence (Box 57)
    - N - New Dominoes (Box 57)
    - P - Poems (Box 57)
    - P - Palazzeschi translations (Box 57)
    - P - Picasso and the Owl (Box 57)
    - Q - Quarrels of Brist (Box 57)
    - S - Sardinia, 2 (Box 57)
    - A - Atlanta Monthly (Box 58)
    - B- The Balloon Tree - dummies, mock-ups (Box 58)
    - C - Crowell (Box 58)
    - C - Curtis Brown (Box 58)
    - D - Doubleday and Random House - Like a Flower "Novel II" (Box 58)
    - D - Dodson Rader (Box 58)
    - D - Dodson Rader - London Magazine - libel, 2 (Box 58)
    - G - Guggenheim (Box 58)
    - H - Harpers Bazaar (Box 58)
    - H - Harpers Magazine (Box 58)
    - H - Horizon (Box 58)
    - I - In Fair Verona (Box 58)
    - M - Madmoiselle (Box 58)
    - M - Mother's correspondence (Box 58)
    - M - Mondadire Due Vitae (Box 58)
    - M - Michael Joseph (Box 58)
    - N - New Directions (Box 58)
    - P - Partisan Review (Box 58)
    - P - Paris Review (Box 58)
    - S - Scribners (Box 58)
    - S - The Stone in the Hourglass (Box 58)
    - V - Various - Dog Star (Box 58)
    - V - Various - The Hero Continues (Box 58)
    - V- Various - Miscellaneous Magazines (Box 58)
    - Unlabeled artwork (Box 58)
    - Stories - unpublished (Box 59)
    - Stories from Yellow Paper - misc. notes and drafts (Box 59)
    - In the Cage - Fichi D'India (Box 59)
    - Publicity, reviews, etc. (Box 59)
    - Manuscripts and notes (Box 59)
    - Poetry, 2 (Box 59)
    - Poems (Box 59)
    - Melton (Box 59)
    - Autobiography, 1940 (Box 59)
    - Autobiography, 1941 (Box 59)
    - Autobiography, 1942 (Box 59)
    - Current work (Box 59)
    - Articles on T. Williams (Box 59)
    - Miscellaneous letters (Box 59)
    - The Weigela Club - early drafts of., etc. (Box 59)
    - Clipping: Stonelle (Box 59)
    - Italian Articles (Box 59)
    - Today Is Saturday Night (Box 59)
    - Like a Flower (Box 59)
    - Eliz. McFadder (Box 59)
    - Anne Ryan - Journal (Box 59)
    - Anne Ryan, 3 (Box 59)
    - Anne Wood - published, 3 (Box 59)
  - Other papers, circa 1960-1999; Series VII; 1.42; (2 boxes)
    Arranged into two groupings: Business files and Subject files.
    - Business files
      - Contracts - miscellaneous (Box 60)
      - Copyrights, 2 (Box 60)
    - Subject files
      - Fritz Bultmann (Box 60)
      - Fritz Bultmann, 2 (Box 60)
      - Pavel Tchelitchew (Box 60)
      - Joseph Cornell (Box 60)
      - Various material regarding writing (Box 60)
        Includes The Oxford American Magazine (1995).
      - Photo: Newspaper Clippings, 1960s (Box 60)
      - Material regarding Tchelitchew - Morse Howe (Box 60)
      - Clippings - mainly Italian - Two People (Box 60)
      - Button & Henry (Box 60)
        Contains material regarding Henrietta Michaelson.
      - Various material, 1990s (Box 61)
        Includes limited correspondence, clippings, photocopies and printed material.
      - The Warm Country - reviews, 1962 (Box 61)
      - Two People - reviews and correspondence, 1965 (Box 61)
      - Clippings, reviews, letters, various books, 1960 (Box 61)
      - Book clippings, 1960s-1970s (Box 61)
      - Reviews - Emblems of Conduct, circa 1964 (Box 61)
  - Sandy Campbell papers, circa 1940-1999; Series VIII; 1.25; (2 boxes)
    - Art scrapbook (Box 62 Oversize)
    - School photographs and Kent School diploma (Box 62 Oversize)
    - Photographs by Alfredo Valente (Box 63)
    - Correspondence - clippings from Don's Scrapbook (Box 63)
    - Sandy's Theater scrapbook (Box 63)
    - Photographs (Box 63)
    - Photographs of Paul Cadmus, Lincoln, Fidelma (Box 63)
    - Photographs - Rome, 1964 (Box 63)
    - Photographs, 1940-1941 (Box 63)
    - Photographs - portrait of Windham and Campbell (Box 63)
    - Photographs circa 1948, Correspondence 1990s, 1948, 1990s (Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 63)
    - Current work: Sandy Documents (Box 63)
    - Book reviews, manuscripts (Box 63)
  - Printed material, 1944-2004; Series IX; 2; (2 boxes)
    - Magazines, 1947-1973; 2 (Box 64)
    - "Sur" (Box 64)
    - Various Material (Box 64)
      Includes The James White Review, Isadora Duncan: Muse of Modernism catalog, various postcards; and Martha Graham by Carl Van Vechten.
    - View Magazine, 1944-1946 (Box 64)
    - Various Play Bills, 1945-1948 (Box 64)
    - View Magazine, 1942-1945 (Box 64)
    - Various Play Bills, 1948-1995 (Box 64)
    - Various Play Bills, 1941-1980s (Box 64)
    - Various Play Bills, 1945-1989 (Box 64)
    - Atlanta Intown, newspaper, 2004 August (Box 64)
    - New-Story magazine, 1951 October (Box 64)
      Also contains The American Pen magazine (Fall 1974).
    - Matchbooks - two boxes, 2 (Box 65)
    - U.S. Stamps (Box 65)
    - Interview, 1992 December (Box 20 Oversize)
    - Joe's First Issue (Box 20 Oversize)
  - Audiovisual materials, 1967-1999; Series X; 0.42; (1 box)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Interview with Donald Windham on Joseph Cornell", 1980 December; 1 (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099365323)
    - "Tennessee Williams/New Orleans Literary Festival: Memories of the Youthful and Older Tennessee", 1997; 1 (Box 66, Item barcode 39002099365331)
    - "Tennessee Williams/New Orleans Literary Festival: Memories of the Youthful and Older Tennessee", 1997; 1 (Box 66)
      This audiocassette is a duplicate. It has not been digitized.
    - "Dakin Williams in New Orleans", 1992 March 26; YCALMSS424_0001; 1; 01:04:51; The tape has very poor video quality. (Box 66, Item barcode 39002102317402)
      A note belonging with the tape reads: For George T. Parsons III with affection - Dakin Williams July 25, 1992 Filmed March 26, 1992.
    - "Don's Talk: Rome '67", film reel, 1967 (Box 66)
    - "Omnibus: Joseph Cornell", YCALMSS424_0002; 1; 00:51:06 (Box 66, Item barcode 39002102317410)